George King IV Alternative Press Collection
© 2008 University of Connecticut
George King IV Alternative Press Collection.
undated, 2001-2003.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
King, George, IV [collector].
2.5 linear feet.
The collection includes publications, newspapers and fliers concerning the anti-war activities, independent media, People's Summit (September 2001, Washington, D.C.) the Attack on America (September 2001), and World Economic Forum (February 2002).
MSS20010100
Scope and Content
The collection includes publications, newspapers and fliers concerning the independent media, People's Summit (September 2001, Washington, D.C.) the Attack on America (September 2001), and World Economic Forum (February 2002).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials documenting activities of organizations and individuals considered "alternative" to the mainstream of American culture, politics, society, and lifestyle. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
Materials were placed in appropriately sized folders and arranged alphabetically by topic or organization.
Separated Material
Hat City Free Press issues have been interfiled with the Dodd Periodicals holdings.
Another World is possible. Dodd B6421
Desire for change. Dodd XAII.2 no. 109
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Underground press publications.; Radicalism.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Fliers. [printed matter]
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated to Archives & Special Collections in October 2001 by Mr. King. Additional materials continue to be added periodically.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, 2001-2003
  - Anti-War (Iraq)
    - D.C. Free Press, July-October, 2001 (Box 2)
    - "Fighting for Our Lives", 2002 (Box 1:4)
    - Hartford Peace Rally, 2002 (Box 1:5)
    - Hartford Undercurrent, April, May, June, July, 2003 (Box 2:24)
    - Hat City Free Press, May, August, 2002 (Box Dodd Periodicals)
    - Hat City Free Press, May, 2003 (Box Dodd Periodicals)
    - Iraq Talk and Slide show (John Humphries), 2002 (Box 1:6)
    - Maine Free Press, Autumn, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Posters, undated (Box 2)
    - War Times, August, September, December/January, April-May, May-June, July-August, 2002-2003 (Box 1:7)
  - Attack on America, 2001 (Box 1:8)
  - General, 2001 (Box 1:10)
    - CT Green Times, Spring, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Echoes from the Streets, April, 2003 (Box 2)
    - Green Party of Connecticut, undated (Box 1:14)
    - Scope, July, 2003 (Box 1:15)
  - Indymedia (Box 2:16)
    - D.C. Free Press, 2001
      - V. 1, #2 July/August
      - V. 1, #3 August/September
      - V. 1, #4 Sept/October
    - Ephemera, 2001
    - Hat City Free Press, September, 2001 (Box Dodd Periodicals)
    - The Indypendent, 2001
      - Special Issue #1, September (copy)
      - Special Issue #2, September
  - People's Summit, 2001 (Box 1:11)
  - Poster, 2001 (Box 2)
  - World Economic Forum (Box 1:13)
    - Chronicle of the New York State Greens, v.2, issue 2 Spring, 2001 (Box 2:17)
    - Hat City Free Press, February, 2001 (Box Dodd Periodicals)
    - The Indypendent, February, 2002 (Box 2:18)